為什麼他們餵他比我們好？
How come they feed him better than us?
哦，看誰又送我的餐遲到了
Oh, look who's late with my meal again.
呃，伊瓦爾 Uh, Ivar.
你願意做個紳士，並給我拿些橄欖來，拜託？
Would you be a gentlemen and get me more olives, please?
畢竟，今天是我的生日
It's my birthday, after all.
伸出你的手
Give out your hand.
好吧，我咬一口
All right, I'll bite.
我要再喝點酒
I'm going for more wine.
再見，伊瓦爾
So long, Ivar.
是的 Yes.
伊瓦爾？ 伊瓦爾！
Ivar? Ivar!
你永遠逃不掉
You will never escape.
奧丁和索爾會找到你的
Odin and Thor will find you.
我已經逃跑了
I've already escaped.
洛基逃跑了！ 搜索每個房間！
Loki has escaped! Search every room!
搜查城堡！
Search the castle!
洛基! Loki!
現在就停止這種瘋狂
Stop this madness right now.
塵世會倒下
Midgard will fall.
而我會重新種植這棵樹
And I will replant this tree.
當這種情況發生時，你或者可以加入我
When that happens, you can either join me
或者你可以反對我
or you can be against me.
但我向你保證，一切都太晚了
But I assure you, it will be too late,
因為我將擁有所有的力量
for I will have all the power.
衹有傻瓜才會尋找非常虛弱的世界
Only a fool would seek a shattered world.
沒有什麼可以讓你統治了！
There would be nothing left for you to rule!
我不會允許你
I will not allow you
來完成拉格納羅克的命運
to fulfill the destiny of Ragnarok.
這不是我希望的答案
It was not the answer I'd hoped for,
但是如果你擋了路，那就這樣吧!
but if you get in the way, so be it.
你的魔法起不了作用...
Your magic does not work...
在我的王座房間裡
in my throne room.
我不需要魔法來打敗你衰老的靈魂
I don't need magic to defeat your old, decrepit soul.
沒有你的權杖，你什麼都不是！
Without your staff, you are nothing!
洛基，現在住手
Loki, stop this now.
什麼，你害怕一旦我釋放了大灰狼
What, are you afraid that once I release the Great Wolf,
它會追捕你，並完成它的使命
that he will hunt you down and fulfill his destiny
藉著毀滅你？仍然可以有和平
by destroying you? There can still be peace.
我不喜歡你的判決
I took no pleasure in your sentencing.
然而我在那裡，在那地牢裡腐爛
Yet there I was, rotting away in that dungeon.
我被人民...
I spent far too long idly by...
我們的人民嘲笑和嘲笑太久了
mocked and ridiculed by the people, our people,
當你坐在王座的房間裡
while you've sat there in that throne room,
對我們的世界無所事事
doing nothing for our world.
我可以完成那些年前開始的事情！
I can finish what I started all those years ago!
投降，洛基 投降!
Surrender, Loki. Surrender!
索爾正在路上
Thor is on his way.
而且你無法逃脫
And you have no escape.
投降? Surrender?
我纔剛剛開始，奧丁
I am just getting started, Odin.
啊！Aah!
索爾! Thor!
啊...Ugh...
奧丁...Odin...
我警告過你
I warned you.
父親! Father!
哦! 不! Oh! No!
父親 父親! Father. Father!
拉格...拉格納羅克
Rag...Ragnarok.
父親，省省你的力氣
Father, save your strength.
我會尋求幫助 不，不
I'll get help. No, no.
洛基...洛基要去塵世...
Loki...Loki is going to Midgard...
去喚醒芬利爾
to awaken Fenrir
並摧毀九洲之樹
and destroy the tree of the Nine Realms
然後在洛基的控制下再生！
that will then regrow in Loki's control!
芬利爾...芬利爾被監禁了
Fenrir...Fenrir was imprisoned.
永遠不會被釋放
Never to be set free.
凡人，他們不明白
The mortals, they don't understand.
他們不明白他們...他們釋放了什麼
They don't understand what they...they have released.
我該怎麼阻止它，父親？
How do I stop it, Father?
你需要找到...
You need to find...
另一半的瓦格護身符
the other half of the Vargr amulet.
如果兩半被放在一起
If the two halves are put together,
他們可以消滅大灰狼
they could destroy the Great Wolf.
你必須跟著他 你不能讓他成功
You must follow him. You cannot let him succeed.
我在哪裡可以找到護身符？
Where do I find the amulet?
它被送給了一個凡人的國王
It was given to a mortal king
許多以年前
many years ago.
即使是我...也不知道它在哪裡
Even I...do not know where it resides.
你需要找到芬利爾的墳墓！
You need to find Fenrir's tomb!
父親...父親？
Father...Father?
父親! 父親!
Father! Father!
那是一個2.6級
That's a 2.6.
你怎麼認為，格雷斯，2.6級？
What do you think, Grace, 2.6.?
蛤? Huh?
那次地震 什麼地震？
That earthquake. What earthquake?
把刀柄遞給我
Hand me the hilt.
你為什麼一直在看那個？
Why do you keep looking at that?
看到這個了嗎？
See this?
是啊! 看起來像風箏
Yeah. Looks like a kite.
你認為土著美國人在
You think indigenous Native Americans are
放風箏嗎？這是200年前的
flying kites? Is this some kind of
體育用品店嗎？
sporting goods store from 200 years ago?
你能至少假裝你知道岩石雕刻嗎？
Can you at least pretend you know petroglyphs?
嘿，你要一位地質學家？我是你所要的人
Hey, you want a geologist? I'm your guy.
你想找人喝杯咖啡，還是你的人
You want someone to do a coffee run, still your guy.
你想要有人識別土著符號？
You want somebody to identify indigenous symbols?
不是你的人 顯然地
Not your guy. Clearly.
此外，這不是土著美洲人
And besides, this isn't indigenous Native Americans.
這是什麼? What is it?
這是大灰狼，芬利爾的象徴
This is the symbol of Fenrir, the Great Wolf.
他是個神，有能力摧毀奧丁
He was a god, with the power to destroy Odin.
奧丁？ 就像索爾 像那個奧丁？
Odin? Like Thor. Like that Odin?
是的 Yep.
而且傳說芬利爾是如此卑鄙
And legend has it that Fenrir was so mean
而且不受控制的他試圖開啟時代的終結
and uncontrolled that he tried to start the end of times.
如果他要實現他的預言，那麼他會
If he were to fulfill his prophecy, then he would
摧毀九界，併殺死奧丁和他的妻子弗裡格
destroy the Nine Realms and kill Odin and his wife, Frigg.
芬利爾怎麼了？
What happened to Fenrir?
他們抓住了他，並把他囚禁起來
They captured him and imprisoned him
永遠 for all eternity.
希望他不會逃跑
Let's hope he doesn't escape.
格雷斯 Grace.
嘿，阿德裡安 格雷斯剛剛發現了瓦爾哈拉
Hey, Adrian. Grace here just discovered Valhalla.
以及世界末日 這很酷，對嗎？
And the end of the world. That's pretty cool, right?
薩吉亞斯博士希望我們延期
Dr. Sagias wants us to hold off.
為什麼？他擔心
Why? Well, he's worried
我們正在經歷前震
that we're experiencing foreshock
導致了一場大地震
leading up to one big earthquake.
不，他-告訴薩吉亞斯博士
No, he-tell Dr. Sagias you don't know if a foreshock
除非之前發生了更大的地震，否則你不知道前震是否是前震
is a foreshock unless it's preceded by a bigger quake,
而且主要事件可能在幾個月內不會發生
and the main event may not happen for months.
聽著，讓我給他打電話，我會和他談談...
Look, let me just call him, I'll talk to him...
不，不止這些 你什麼意思？
No, it's more than that. What do you mean?
這是一連串的地震，而且它們同時發生
It's a cluster of quakes, and they've been happening
顯然遍及全世界
at the same time and apparently around the whole world.
不，你不可能同時發生兩次地震
No, you can't have two quakes at once,
更不用說一連串了
let alone a cluster of them.
但讓我上網，我會查一下美國地質調查局
But let me get online, and I'll check the USGS,
而且我會看看他們的地震儀，好嗎？
and I'll look at their seismographs, okay?
好的 Okay.
阿德裡安，看
Adrian, look.
遷移期？是啊!
Migration period? Yeah.
維京人 Vikings.
我看得出來
I can see that.
它很容易超過一千年
It's easily over a thousand years old.
阿德裡安，這就是一切
Adrian, this is everything.
我們可以證明維京人穿越了北美
We can prove that Vikings traveled across North America
一路到加利福尼亞
all the way to California,
比任何人想像的都要早
way before anyone ever thought.
這可能是搶劫
It could be a plunder.
你知道，一個戰爭紀念品
You know, a souvenir from battle.
我的意思是，維京人此時已經在紐芬蘭了
I mean, Vikings were already in Newfoundland by this time.
那很好 但仔細看看這些岩石
That's fine. But look closely at these rocks.
我看到了其他符號的岩石雕刻，都是挪威文
I see petroglyphs of other symbols, all Norse.
這毫無意義 阿德裡安
This makes no sense. Adrian,
這是一座維京人的陵墓，我們衹要進去就行了
this is a Viking tomb, and we just have to get inside.
沒有維京人到這麼遠的西部的記錄
There's no record of Vikings making it this far west.
我知道！I know!
這就像...科普和馬什
This is like when...Cope and Marsh
發現了巨大的恐龍骨骼
discovered huge dinosaur bones
在19世紀的美國
in the United States in the 1800s.
沒人知道它們能走這麼遠
No one knew they could make it this far.
抱歉 我打不開它
Sorry. I can't open it
直到我們把一切都弄清楚
until we get the all clear.
我們如此近了 我們只需要打開這個墳墓
We're so close. We just have to open this tomb.
我會進去，我進去看看一會兒裡面
I'll go inside, I'll see inside for just a moment.
一週後我會在這裡進行實地調查
I'll get a site survey out here in a week.
我可以在不到兩週的時間內獲得認證
I can get it certified in less than two weeks.
兩週對一座墳墓來說沒有什麼不同
Two weeks makes no difference for a tomb
它在這裡已經有一千年了
that's been here for a thousand years.
我會讓我的團隊來保護這個地點
I'll get my team here to secure the site
所以薩吉亞斯博士更舒服
so Dr. Sagias is more comfortable.
好的 然後我們會在一週內扭轉局面
Okay. And then we'll have this turned around in a week.
大家還好嗎？
Everyone okay?
它自己打開了
It opened by itself.
把岩石鋸給我
Give me the rock saw.
我要去找人幫忙
I'm going to go get help.
我會和薩吉亞斯博士談談
I'll talk to Dr. Sagias.
嗨! 是的，我現在需要和薩吉亞斯博士談談
Hi. Yes, I need to speak to Dr. Sagias now.
現場是艾德裡安
It's Adrian at the site.
手電筒? Flashlight?
它是30,000流明
It's 30,000 lumens.
那是什麼嗶音？那是我
What's that beeping? That's me.
氫含量非常高
Hydrogen levels are really high.
危險嗎? Dangerous?
可能是門開的時候發生的
Probably happened when the door opened.
是的，當氫遇到氧時
Yeah, when hydrogen meets oxygen,
它相當具有爆炸性
it's pretty explosive.
是的-它也製造水
Yeah-it also makes water.
是的 Yeah.
尼克，你不會相信剛剛發生的事
Nick, you won't believe what just happened.
這裡沒什麼
Not much in here.
也許我們不是第一個打開它的人
Maybe we're not the first to open it.
不 維京人的陵墓不像埃及的陵墓
No. Viking tombs were not like Egyptian tombs.
非常基本 Very basic.
我很驚訝它有岩石雕刻
I'm surprised it has petroglyphs.
一定是某個特別的人
Must have been someone special.
或者別的什麼
Or something.
我沒有看到屍體
I don't see a body.
維京人通常被火化
Vikings were usually cremated.
所以這不是墳墓？
So this isn't a tomb?
我不知道 I don't know.
可能是個聖陵
Could be a shrine.
符號上寫了什麼？
What did the symbols say?
抱歉 Sorry.
剛剛和薩吉亞斯博士談過 他不想我們在這裡
Just talked to Dr. Sagias. He doesn't want us in here.
拜託，你現在一定在開我玩笑
Come on. You gotta be kidding me right now.
他想派一名結構工程師
He wants to send a structural engineer
來這裡確保它的安全
out here to make sure it's safe.
好的 Okay.
來吧，格雷斯
Come on, Grace.
知道了 Got it.
格雷斯，來吧!
Grace, come on.
肯定是挪威人
Definitely Norse.
我看到更多的狼象形文字
I see more of the wolf hieroglyphs.
芬利爾? Fenrir?
是的，但是...Yes, but...
我也看到了一些美洲高山族的符號
I see some Native American symbols, too,
比如先早 通瓦符號
like early. Tongva symbols.
所以，這座陵墓是一個合資企業
So, this tomb was a joint venture
界於土著部落和維京人之間？
between indigenous tribes and the Vikings?
做個猜測，但是...
Taking a guess, but...
也許這兩個團體都建造了這個
maybe both groups built this
因為他們都有既定的興趣
because they both had a vested interest.
在建造維京人陵墓？
In building a Viking tomb?
通瓦部落為什麼要這樣做？
Why would the Tongva tribes do that?
尊敬? Respect?
或者恐懼 Or fear.
看看這些符號
Look at these symbols.
那是瓦爾克努特，死亡的象徴
That's a Valknut, symbol of death.
那是伊格德拉西爾，九界之樹
That's Yggdrasil, tree of the Nine Realms.
太陽，那是壞精靈的通加語
That's Tongva for bad spirit, sun.
也許這不是墳墓
Maybe it's not a tomb.
也許是別的東西
Maybe it's something else.
像是什麼？Like what?
任何東西 Anything.
一個通道、一個房間、一個神龕
A passageway, a room, a shrine.
一個監獄 A prison.
為了狼神
For the wolf god
想要吃掉太陽，摧毀九界
that wants to eat the sun and destroy the Nine Realms.
住口 Stop.
兩種文化合作建造監獄 為什麼？
Two cultures teaming together to build a prison. Why?
哇，哇! 我不這麼認為
Whoa, whoa. I don't think so.
對不起，先生 不要碰我
Excuse me, sir. Do not touch me.
這是一個安全區域 我們需要看一些身份證明
This is a secure area. We need to see some I.D.
一些身份證明?
Some I.D.?
身份證明是什麼？你不知道我是誰嗎？
What is I.D.? Do you not know who I am?
先生，你可以是亞伯拉罕·林肯
Sir, you could be Abraham Lincoln
和約翰·威爾克斯·布斯一起走進來
walking in here with John Wilkes Booth.
而且我還需要身份證明
And I'd still need I.D.
顯然是你的一些朋友
Clearly must be some friends of yours.
你不負責，是嗎？
You're not in charge, are you?
身份證明 I.D.
別再提身份證明了
Enough with the I.D.
誰負責？
Who's in charge?
那就是尼克.薩吉亞斯博士
That'd be Dr. Nick Sagias,
奧廷卡博物館執行主任
executive director at the Odinkar Museum.
那個傢伙 That guy.
薩吉亞斯博士
Dr. Sagias.
帥哥 Handsome fellow.
我可以進去嗎？
May I go in?
我需要呈報這個 不，你不能
I need to call this in. No, you don't.
不，我不能 No, I don't.
午安，薩吉亞斯博士
Afternoon, Dr. Sagias.
很高興見到你
It's great to see you.
你想讓我帶團隊
Would you like me to get the team
並到現場見你嗎？
and meet you at the site?
沒有必要
Won't be necessary.
好的 All right.
聽起來不錯
Sounds good.
我的朋友，我在監獄裡待太久了
Been in prison far too long, my friend.
我知道你所經歷的什麼
I know what you're going through.
等待結束了
The wait is over.
我真不敢相信我錯過了那個
I can't believe I missed that.
什麼? What?
那是蘇利特
That's thulite.
這就是為什麼它有粉紅對其着色
That's why it has that pink tint to it.
蘇利特？是的，是挪威語
Thulite? Yeah, it's Norwegian.
這些是巨大的岩石
These are huge rocks.
他們在這裡幹什麼？
What are they doing here?
他們會周遊全國
Would they travel across the country
以成噸的蘇利特？
with tons of thulite?
你在加州找不到蘇利特
You can't find thulite in California.
不是一千年前 我是說，他們發現了一些東西
Not a thousand years ago. I mean, they found something
與塞爾湖相似，但很深
similar at Searles Lake, but deep.
真的很深-你需要19世紀的工程
Really deep-you'd need 19th century engineering
來粹取它 嘿，崔博士
to extract it. Hey, Dr. Choi.
早上好，哈樂德
Morning, Harold.
薩吉亞斯說他今天要來嗎？
Did Sagias say he was coming in today?
沒有，我剛剛和他通了電話 為什麼？
No, I just spoke to him on the phone. Why?
我很確定他在這裡
I'm pretty sure he's here.
什麼? 我想他在墳墓裡
What? I think he's in the tomb.
你授權使用炸藥了嗎？
Did you authorize the explosives?
我為什麼要這麼做？哈樂德，打911
Why would I do that? Harold, call 911.
尼克? 哈囉?
Nick? Hello?
格雷斯，我覺得房間變大了
Grace, I think the room got bigger.
另一扇門開了！
Another door opened!
尼克! 哇，哇，哇！
Nick! Whoa, whoa, whoa!
有很多氫氣！我們應該在外面等
It's a lot of hydrogen! We should wait outside.
聽著，我猜這次是
Listen, my guess is this time
有一個揮發性的化學反應
there was a volatile chemical reaction.
另一扇門 誰在乎呢？走吧！
Another door. Who cares? Let's go!
我們在找尼克
We're looking for Nick.
不，這是一個剛剛爆炸的不穩定地點
No, this is a volatile site that just exploded
而且可能殺了某人 我們得走了
and possibly killed someone. We need to go.
他可能會受傷 崔博士？
He could be hurt. Dr. Choi?
急救人員正在趕來
First responders are on their way,
但他們有問題，因為這是一個挖掘現場
but they've got questions because it's a dig site.
哈囉? Hello?
帕特裡克，我們走
Patrick, let's go.
帕特裡克! Patrick!
帕特裡克...Patrick...
帕特裡克! 阿德裡安
Patrick! Adrian.
帕特裡克，我們走
Patrick, let's go.
等等，那是薩吉亞斯博士
Wait, wait, that's Dr. Sagias.
哦，我的天啊!
Oh my God.
尼克? Nick?
別碰我 Don't touch me.
沒事的，薩吉亞斯博士
It's okay, Dr. Sagias.
你在挖掘現場
You're at the dig site.
那發生了爆炸
There was an explosion.
尼克，是我，阿德裡安·奎因
Nick, it's me, Adrian Quinn.
你...你受傷了嗎？你沒事吧？
Are you...Are you hurt? Are you okay?
我不需要你的幫助，好嗎？
I don't want your help, okay?
他們找到他了
They found him.
是的，他衹是有點震驚
Yeah, he's just a little stunned.
好了，各位，這裡不安全
All right, everybody, it's not safe here.
我們必須把所有人都救出來
We got to get everybody out.
先生? 薩吉亞斯博士
Sir? Dr. Sagias,
我帶你到地面，好嗎？
I'm going to lead you to the surface, all right?
離我遠點 你們所有的人！
Stay away from me. All of you!
尼克 是我，格雷斯
Nick. It's me, Grace.
我現在不需要你的幫助
I do not require your assistance at this time.
你為什麼在這裡，尼克？
Why are you here, Nick?
我來...I came...
親自來訪問芬利爾監獄
to visit the prison of Fenrir myself.
你怎麼知道這是芬利爾的監獄？
How did you know this was the prison of Fenrir?
我們需要出去外面
We need to go outside.
這個房間太不穩定了
This room is too unstable.
我們需要離開
We need to leave.
那很好 我和帕特裡克一起去
That's fine. I'll go with Patrick here.
你們都離開
You all leave.
好的 Okay.
你找到他了？我很好，很好，衹是-是的
You got him? I'm fine, fine, just-yeah.
呃-呃 Uh-uh.
你覺得尼克看起來不太對勁了嗎？
Did Nick seem off to you?
有人說他會出現在現場上
No one said anything about him showing up to the site.
他就是這樣
He's like that.
是的，但你剛剛和他談過
Yeah, but you just talked to him.
我和他通了電話
I talked to him on the phone.
他可能正在去現場的路上
He could have been on his way to the site.
對 Right.
看，尼克很古怪
Look, Nick is eccentric.
可能被爆炸震暈了
Could have been stunned from the blast.
你注意到他沒有跛行嗎？他總是拿著枴杖
Did you notice he's not limping? He always has a cane.
我的意思是，我們應該聽他說，或者至少看到他
I mean, we should have heard him or at least seen him.
他是怎麼從我們身邊溜過去的？
How'd he sneak past us?
我要打幾通電話 我不知道發生了什麼
I'm gonna make a few calls. I'm not sure what's going on,
但這感覺不對 我要回去
but it doesn't feel right. I'm going to go back.
什麼? What?
我衹是想知道你是否值得拯救
I was just wondering if you were worth saving.
你說什麼? Excuse me?
我以為你想讓我幫你離開這裡，薩吉亞斯博士
I thought you wanted me to help you out of here, Dr. Sagias.
那就幫忙吧!
Then help.
這是安全部門，我是葛列格
You reached security, this is Greg.
我能幫你什麼？
How can I help you?
是的 嗨，我是格雷斯.崔
Yes. Hi, I'm Grace Choi.
我是與薩吉亞斯合作的考古學家之一
I'm one of the archeologists working with Sagias.
我想知道我是否可以和他談談
I was wondering if I could speak with him.
恐怕薩吉亞斯博士正在開會
I'm afraid that Dr. Sagias is in a meeting.
你得晚點再打來
You have to call back later.
他正在開會？
He's in a meeting?
他去現場了嗎？
Did he go to the site?
沒有，我大約10分鐘前剛到他家吃午飯
No, I just buzzed in his lunch about 10 minutes ago.
他一整天待在博物館了
He's been at the museum all day.
好的 謝謝 當然
Okay. Thanks. Of course.
還有什麼我能幫忙的嗎？
Is there anything else I can help with?
有什麼問題嗎？
Is there anything wrong?
你能讓他開會完後打電話給我嗎？
Could you have him call me when he's done?
告訴他這很重要
Tell him it's important.
當然 我會讓他馬上給你回電話
Certainly. I'll have him call you back at once.
謝謝，葛列格
Thanks, Greg.
哈樂德 是的?
Harold. Yeah?
把你的無線電扔給我
Toss me your radio.
帕特裡克？奎因？
Patrick? Quinn?
聽到嗎，完畢？
Come in, over?
有人能聽到我說話嗎，完畢？
Can anyone hear me, over?
來吧，跟我來
Come on. Follow me.
這都是什麼？
What is all this?
一個哨所站
A sentry station.
警衛？為了什麼？
Guards? For what?
芬利爾 Fenrir.
尼克! Nick!
尼克，住手！終於
Nick, stop! At last.
住手 Stop.
對不起，像這樣的事情是有程序的
I'm sorry, but there are procedures for stuff like this.
我很抱歉？I'm sorry?
你不能只從挖掘現場拿走東西
You can't just take things from an excavation site.
我們必須記錄下來
We have to log it.
但更重要的是，我們現在必須離開這裡
But more importantly, we have to get out of here now.
薩吉亞斯博士...
Dr. Sagias...
打開骨灰盒
Open the urn.
尼克! 現在 打開骨灰盒
Nick! Now. Open the urn.
帕特裡克 帕特裡克，住手！
Patrick. Patrick, stop!
我不能呼吸
I can't breathe.
好多了 謝謝你，博士
Much better. Thank you, Doctor.
沒有你的幫助，我永遠無法
Without your assistance, I would've never
找回大灰狼的毒牙
been able to retrieve the Great Wolf's fang.
你不能移動它
You can't remove that.
我不明白 I don't understand.
你是誰？Who are you?
我的禮貌在哪裡？
Where are my manners?
為什麼，我是洛基
Why, I'm Loki.
離他遠一點
Get away from him.
那不是尼克
That's not Nick.
就是那個傢伙！
That's the guy!
就是那個通過我的傢伙
That's the guy that got past me.
你想要什麼？
What do you want?
當然，這理所應當地是我的
What's rightfully mine, of course.
他在某種程度上控制著帕特裡克
He's controlling Patrick somehow.
格雷斯，我們必須離開這裡
Grace, we got to get out of here.
你對帕特裡克做了什麼？
What have you done to Patrick?
很不幸，奧丁成功了
Well, unfortunately, Odin made it
所以，上帝無法挖掘出這隻大灰狼
so that a God is unable to unearth the Great Wolf.
所以我需要一個凡人
So I needed a mortal,
而這裡的好博士很樂意也很能幹
and the good doctor here was willing and able.
而現在我有了毒牙...
And now that I have the fang...
還有一件事要做
there's just one more thing to do.
帕特裡克! Patrick!
不! 離開這裡！走!
No! Get out of here! Go!
救你自己！走! 啊！
Save yourself! Go! Ah!
你聽到他了，救你自己
You heard him, save yourself.
走! 救你自己！走!
Go! Save yourselves! Go!
啊！Ah!
你沒事吧？是的，我想是的
Are you okay? Yeah, I think so.
他在那裡 There he is.
我想知道你什麼時候會出現，索爾
I was wondering when you'd show up, Thor.
看起來你沒有想像中那麼善於
Looks like you were not as good
隱藏自己的行蹤
at hiding your whereabouts as you think.
你將為你對阿斯加德的罪行付出代價
You will pay for your crimes against Asgard.
罪行？什麼罪行？
解放這個星球？解放凡人
Liberating this planet? Freeing the mortals.
我相信是你犯的罪行，索爾
I believe you're the one committing the crime, Thor.
恐怕太晚了，因為芬利爾甦醒了
I'm afraid it's too late, for Fenrir is awake.
世界末日即將到來
The end of the world is near.
我必須跑走了
I must run.
不 不! 洛基！
No. No! Loki!
洛基！Loki!
你還好嗎？是的，我想是的
You okay? Yeah, I think so.
等等，格雷斯！
Wait, Grace!
等等，等等 Wait, wait.
對不起 Excuse me.
嗨，呃...Hi, uh...
我是，呃...格雷斯
I'm, uh...Grace.
我是格雷斯.崔博士
I'm Dr. Grace Choi.
我是這次挖掘的現場經理
I'm site manager at this excavation.
嗯，呃-呃 Um, uh-uh.
那是洛基，所以...
That's Loki, so...
你一定是索爾
You must be Thor.
你知道我的名字？
You know of my name?
怎麼知道? How?
噢...錘子
Well...the hammer.
雷神之錘？Mjolnir?
你知道他嗎？
You know of it?
北歐神話是我的專長
Norse mythology is my specialty.
噢...Well...
我猜，不是神話
Not mythology, I guess.
你研究了我們
You studied us.
那麼你可能知道洛基在哪裡
Then you may know where Loki is.
你可以幫我
You can help me.
嗯，也許？Um, maybe?
你的世界的命運取決於它
The fate of your world depends upon it
還有你對我們的了解
and your knowledge of us.
噢，當你這樣說的時候
Well, when you put it like that.
跟我來 Come with me.
好的 Okay.
芬利爾的毒牙 不要碰那個
The Fang of Fenrir. Do not touch that.
等等，你臉上的斑紋怎麼了？
Wait, what happened to the markings on your face?
神的戰爭畫作
War paint of the gods.
它在戰鬥中顯示出來
It manifests during battle.
等等-嘿！Wait-hey!
那是伊格德拉西爾，九界之樹
That's Yggdrasil, the tree of the Nine Realms.
你知道它？
You know of it?
是的 Yeah.
基本上每個分支都包含宇宙的一部分
Basically each branch holds a part of the universe.
地球是它的一部分
Earth is part of it.
這就是洛基追求的
This is what Loki is after.
他尋找來摧毀這棵樹
He seeks to destroy the tree
而種植一種他可以控制的新品種
and plant a new one that he could control.
而這就是為什麼他需要芬利爾？
And that's why he needs Fenrir?
洛基可以摧毀這棵樹
Loki can destroy the tree.
但是攻擊每一個領域，這將是困難的
But attacking each realm, that will be difficult.
芬利爾會變得越來越強大
Fenrir will grow stronger and bigger,
而它將吞噬每一個領域
and he will devour each realm.
樹在哪裡？
Where's the tree?
我父親說它在附近
My father said it's nearby.
當芬利爾離它太近時，他被監禁了
Fenrir was imprisoned when he got too close to it.
眾神阻止了芬利爾 我們衹是凡人
The gods stopped Fenrir. We are just mortals.
沒有人要求你這麼做
No one is asking you to do this.
我將親自接受這個挑戰
I will take on this challenge myself.
不，我們不能讓帕特裡剋死
No, we can't let Patrick die.
你的朋友是對的
Your friend is right.
芬利爾變得更加強大
Fenrir grows more powerful
而你的朋友，他將永遠消失
and your friend, he will disappear forever.
我們可以阻止他們
We can stop them.
這就是我喜歡你們這種人的地方
This is what I like about your kind.
機會對你不利
The odds are against you.
然而你們卻選擇了為彼此而戰
Yet you choose to fight for one another.
我們能和他們戰鬥嗎？不
Can we fight them? No.
衹要告訴我他們在哪裡，我會自己和他們戰鬥
Just tell me where they are and I will fight them on my own.
不，你需要我的幫助，我和你一起去
No. You want my help, that I'm going with you.
我也是 Me, too.
固執、愚蠢
Stubborn, foolish.
但是充滿了勇氣
But full of heart.
好的 我們將一起旅行
Fine. We will travel together.
所以我們要去哪裡？
So where are we going?
洛基用瓦格護身符喚醒了芬利爾
Loki has awakened Fenrir with the Vargr amulet.
但他衹有一半
But he only has one half.
如果我們在他意識到他的錯誤之前找到另一半
If we find the other half before he realizes his mistake,
我們有機會阻止芬利爾
we have a chance of stopping Fenrir
來吞噬樹木
from devouring the tree.
所以我們必須找到另一半的護身符
So we have to locate the other half of the amulet.
的確 Indeed.
薩吉亞斯 是的
Sagias. Yes.
這是什麼？不是什麼，是誰
What is this? Not a what, who.
尼古拉斯·薩吉亞斯博士
Doctor Nicholas Sagias.
如果有人知道護身符的後半部分在哪裡
If anyone knows where to locate the second half of the amulet,
他知道 he does.
那是芬利爾
That is Fenrir.
它此刻變得更加強大
He grows more powerful by the moment.
如果我們不阻止洛基
If we do not stop Loki,
芬利爾將勢不可擋
Fenrir will be unstoppable.
這把錘子太不可思議了
This hammer is amazing.
沒有人能揮舞雷神之錘...
No one can wield Mjolnir...
除非他們值得
unless they are worthy.
當然 Of course.
這是最令人印象深刻的輸送方式
This is the most impressive form of transportation.
你能聯繫到薩吉亞斯博士嗎？
Have you been able to reach Dr. Sagias at all?
嗯-嗯! Mm-mm.
我們對你們這些凡人的了解是有缺陷的
Our knowledge of you mortals is flawed.
你什麼意思？
What do you mean?
噢，上次我們相遇的時候
Well, the last time our paths crossed,
你有劍和船
you had swords and ships.
你最後一次在地球是什麼時候，確切地？
When was the last time you were on Earth, exactly?
早在你的時代之前
Long before your time.
我們人類已經走過了漫長的道路
We humans have come a long way.
另一次地震？
Another quake?
抓穩了 Hold on.
抓穩了! Hold on!
你在做什麼？我們必須找到尼克
What are you doing? We have to get to Nick.
我要直接開車過去 我們別無選擇
I'm gonna drive right through. We don't have another choice.
哦，太棒了
Oh, fantastic.
你會成為一個最令人畏懼的華爾基莉(奧丁神的十二婢女之一)
You would have made a most formidable Valkyrie.
我會認為這是一種恭維
I'll take that as a compliment.
拜託，不要再這樣做了
Please, don't do that again.
是的! 再一次，再一次，再一次 走吧！是的
Yes! Again, again, again. Let's go! Yes.
哈囉? 我是格雷斯.崔！
Hello? It's Grace Choi!
奎因，再嘗試聯繫一下尼克
Quinn, try and reach Nick again.
好的 Okay.
讓開 我會打開這扇門
Step aside. I will open this door.
抱歉 阿德裡安？
Sorry. Adrian?
薩吉亞斯正在等你 進來吧!
Sagias is just waiting for you. Come on in.
所以，這是角色扮演嗎？
So, is this a cosplay thing?
什麼? 那個穿著戲服的傢伙
What? The guy in the costume.
不 No.
我是阿斯加德的索爾，奧丁的兒子
I'm Thor of Asgard, Son of Odin.
你當然是 薩吉亞斯博士？
Of course you are. Dr. Sagias?
哦，嘿! Oh, hey.
所以這個...索爾，是我們的挪威神？
So is this...Thor, our Norse god?
唯一的一個
The one and only.
我知道這聽起來...不，不，不
I know it sounds...No, no, no.
天的盡頭
The end of days.
拉格納羅克
Ragnarok.
然後呢? And?
所以，他知道...古老的語言
So, he knows the...the ancient tongue.
那並不...那並不對我來說有任何意義
That doesn't...that doesn't mean anything to me.
好的 Okay.
所以他是索爾 知道了
So he's Thor. Got it.
我們在浪費時間
We are wasting time.
你知道護身符的另一半在哪裡嗎？
Do you know where the other half of the amulet is?
我想帕特裡克是狼芬利爾的主人吧？
I assume Patrick is the human host for Fenrir the Wolf?
你怎麼...噢，他不在這裡
How did you...Well, he's not here.
如果...如果他死了，你會說些什麼
You would have said something if...if he died.
對嗎? 因為芬利爾需要一個人類宿主 對嗎?
Right? Because Fenrir needs a human host. Correct?
它們變得越來越頻繁
They are becoming more frequent.
芬利爾變得更加強大
Fenrir grows more powerful.
正如我在車裡打電話說的那樣
As I said on the phone in the van,
這就是為什麼我們需要瓦格護身符的第二片
this is why we need the second piece of the amulet of Vargr.
完整的護身符是唯一的東西
The full amulet is the only thing
那可以阻止芬利爾
that can stop Fenrir
並阻止洛基毀滅世界
and prevent Loki from destroying the world.
你知道這是什麼嗎？
So you know what it is?
跟我來 Come with me.
那是一艘埋葬船
That is a burial boat.
不是為了戰鬥？
Not meant for battle?
用於旅行前往至瓦爾哈拉的
Meant for travel to Valhalla.
你不應該從他們的墳墓裡拿走這個
You should not have taken this from their tomb.
我們研究它 從它學習
We study it. Learn from it.
你們擾亂了死者，詛咒了自己
You have cursed yourselves by disturbing the dead.
那些雕像是什麼？
What are those statues?
喬蒙甘德 世界之蛇
Jormungandr. The World Serpent.
我們在早些時候的地震中幾乎失去了它們
We almost lost them in the quake earlier.
你們一到我們就把它們保護好了
We secured them as you guys arrived.
那些是展覽中最珍貴的珠寶之一
Those are one of the crown jewels of the exhibit.
喬蒙甘德是洛基的孩子
Jormungandr is a child of Loki.
你為什麼把這個被詛咒的東西放在這裡？
Why do you have this cursed thing here?
索爾！哇，哇！
Thor! Whoa, whoa!
它們必須被摧毀
They must be destroyed.
等等! Wait!
這東西非常稀有，非常有價值
Very rare and extremely valuable, this stuff.
我們是為護身符來這的
We're here for the amulet.
讓我們把它交給你，這樣我們就可以離開了
Let's just get it to you so we can leave.
太棒了 Great.
來吧，芬利爾
Come, Fenrir.
很快 Soon.
很快，我的孩子
Soon, my child.
就在這裡 Right here.
護身符 The amulet.
漂亮 Beautiful.
當我們把這兩半放在一起時，我們會阻止芬利爾
When we put these halves together, we will stop Fenrir.
現在，我們怎麼找到洛基？
Now, how do we find Loki?
哦，我的天哪!
Oh, my God.
我必須回家 我必須找到我的男朋友
I have to go home. I have to find my boyfriend.
這甚至可能嗎？
Is this even possible?
澳大利亞和紐西蘭
Australia and New Zealand.
海嘯正在向這裡襲來
The tsunami is heading here.
地球將發生地震
The earth will quake.
洪水會來
Floods will come.
末日將近 The end is near.
我們需要到達更高的海拔
We need to get to higher elevation.
我必須走了，我必須...嘿，嘿!
I have to go, I have to...Hey, hey,
你需要和我們在一起
you need to stay with us.
我們會一起離開
We'll leave together.
這可能太晚了
It may be too late.
萬物滅絕已經開始了
Ragnarok has begun.
芬利爾 Fenrir.
你為什麼受傷？
Why do you hurt?
我不明白，你...你不應該感到疼痛
I don't understand, you...you should not feel pain.
你不能 You can't.
我錯過了什麼？
What am I missing?
發生了什麼？
What is happening?
洛基...Loki...
你犯了一個嚴重的錯誤，我的兒子
You've made a grave mistake, my son.
奧丁 Odin.
奧丁，你死了 我是嗎？
Odin, you are dead. Am I?
你死了，你不再是了！
You are dead, you are no more!
而且你在天堂
And you are in Asgard.
不，不，不 No, no, no.
衹是你更多的把戲
Just more of your tricks.
我殺了你 I killed you.
然而...And yet...
你站在我面前
You stand before me.
不，不，這...這隻是一個幻覺
No, no, it's...it's just an illusion.
也許我在華海拉殿的時候還沒有到
Maybe my time in Valhalla was not yet.
也許你害怕了
Maybe you're scared.
你害怕了，這就是你回來的原因
You're scared, that's why you came back.
不 No.
我回來是警告你
I came back to warn you
不要再愚蠢了
to stop this foolishness.
你的這個伎倆會適得其反
This trick of yours will backfire.
預言已經預示了
The prophecy has been foretold.
我將在幾天結束後開始
I will start the end of days.
在找到護身符的另一半之前
You will be dead before you find
你會死的
the other half of the amulet.
另一半？The other half?
你最終會明白這一點的
You would have figured this out eventually.
但我與你有一個交易
But I have a deal for you.
現在馬上停止這
Stop this right now
並且來...坐在我旁邊
and come...sit beside me.
而我們將一起統治
And we shall rule together.
一起? Together?
你一定認為我瘋了
You must think I'm mad.
不 No.
世界末日已經被預言了
The end of days has been foretold.
我會贏的 I will win.
我會摧毀九界
I will destroy the Nine Realms,
而芬利爾會在天堂的大廳裡追捕你
and Fenrir will hunt you down in the halls of Asgard
並吃掉你的心...哦，光榮的奧丁！
and eat your heart out...oh, glorious Odin!
奧丁！奧丁！Odin! Odin!
不! No!
奧丁...奧丁 Odin...Odin.
來吧，芬利爾
Come, Fenrir.
我們必須找到另一半的護身符
We must find the other half of the amulet.
現在 Now.
拿你能拿的一切
Grab whatever you can.
我們必須走了
We have to go.
我知道 I know.
我們應該在這裡等 洛基來了
We should wait here. Loki is coming.
我們還有15分鐘
We have 15 minutes before
在這整座大樓被淹沒之前
this whole building will be underwater.
請拿你能拿到的
Please just grab what you can
而且讓我們上我的車吧!
and let's get in my car.
洛基要來這裡
Loki is coming here.
無意冒犯，但你是不朽的
No offense, but you are immortal.
我們不是 We are not.
我們需要離開
We need to leave.
你有屬於我的東西
You have something that belongs to me.
洛基，你在玩一個危險的遊戲
You are playing a dangerous game, Loki.
我們需要離開 走吧!
We need to leave. Let's go.
把護身符給我，而我保證
Give me the amulet, and I promise
你的死亡將是迅速而無痛的
your deaths will be quick and painless.
停止這種瘋狂，洛基
Stop this madness, Loki.
決不 Never.
那些是什麼東西？
What are those things?
看起來洛基放出他的孩子了
Looks like Loki's let out his children.
他們正在封鎖出口
They're blocking the exits.
我們必須離開這裡，否則我們會死在這裡
We gotta get out of here, or we're going to die here.
等等 Wait.
你在做什麼？等等
What are you doing? Wait!
嘿，嘿，你在幹什麼？
Hey, hey, what are you doing?
這些都沒用
These aren't going to do anything
對抗那些栩栩如生的哨兵
against those animated sentries.
我認為我們別無選擇
I don't think we have any other choice.
護身符 The amulet.
不! No!
洛基！Loki!
洛基去哪兒了？
Where did Loki go?
他逃跑了，而且他擁有了兩半的護身符
He fled and he possesses both halves of the amulet.
芬利爾現在將勢不可擋
Fenrir will be unstoppable now.
對不起，尼克
I'm sorry, Nick.
我們必須走了
We have to go.
海嘯隨時都會到來這裡
The tsunami will be here any minute.
如果我們留在這裡，我們會死的
If we stay here, we're going to die.
當我們到達更高的海拔時，我們會想出另一種方法
We'll figure out another way as we get to higher elevation.
現在不是你進入華海拉殿的時候
This is not your time to enter Valhalla.
阿德裡安！Adrian!
我救不了她
I could not save her.
尼克 Nick.
我們失去了她 我們失去了她，我們失去了阿德裡安
We lost her. We lost her, we lost Adrian.
我們-我們失去了阿德裡安 我們失去了葛列格
We-We lost Adrian. We lost Greg.
而且我們丟了護身符
And we lost the amulet.
沒關係 It's okay.
我們失去了一切 我...無法將他們取回
We lost everything. I...can't get them back.
如果我們還能找到護身符...
If we can still find the amulet...
你能救我們嗎？
can you save us?
太遲了嗎？
Is it too late?
去放棄希望永遠不會太晚
It is never too late to give up hope.
一切都會好起來的 一切都會好起來的
It's going to be okay. It's going to be okay.
我不能這麼做
I can't do this.
我不能 I can't.
不能把他們帶回來
Can't bring them back.
好嗎? Okay?
奧丁，父親 Odin, father.
把你女兒帶回家
Bring your daughter home.
她等待著最後的旅程
She waits for the final journey.
她贏得了她的位置...
Has she earned her place...
或在黑暗中漫遊
Or in darkness to roam.
她走了 She's gone.
好嗎? Okay?
我在這裡 你認為我們能阻止他嗎？
I'm here. Do you think we can stop him?
人類...忍受了很多痛苦
Humans...have endured a lot of suffering
而且幾乎滅絕，但我們倖存了下來
and almost extinction but we survived.
瘟疫，饑荒，乾旱，一切
Plagues, famine, drought, everything.
但是你知道嗎？我們存活了下來
But you know what? We survived.
我們也會活下來
And we will survive this, too.
你必須堅持住...
You have got to hold on...
我們必須對這一切有所作為
we have got to make something of all of this.
絕對地 Absolutely.
很好 Good.
尼克，我們需要找到筆記型電腦
Nick, we need to find the laptop.
我知道 I know.
你找到了嗎？
Did you find it?
沒有，某些更好的
No. Something better.
這是一個象徴勇氣的北歐神符
It's a Valknut.
奧丁的象徴
The symbol of Odin.
你們的恆星 這是一種催化劑
Your star. It's a catalyst.
它可以打開一個用於溝通的入口
It can open a portal for communication.
這上面呢？以連接、電源
What about up here? With connection, power.
諸如此類的事情
Things like that.
父親 父親! Father. Father!
我想肯定以為洛基把你從我們身邊帶走了
I thought surely that Loki had taken you from us.
我的死是不可能的
My death was not to be.
偉大的奧丁
Mighty Odin.
你可以來 你可以來地球幫助我們
You can come. You can come to Earth and help us.
我們需要你 我不能 我太虛弱了
We need you. I can't. I'm too weak.
我對這種聯繫感到驚訝
I'm amazed at this connection.
在這個形狀中
There should be no connection between the Realms
王國與我之間應該沒有任何聯繫
with me in this shape.
是的，噢，凡人
Yes, well, the mortals,
他們現在有北歐神符遺物了
they have the Valknut relic now.
一個...被遺忘很久的年代的遺物
A relic from a...a time long forgotten.
是的，是的 確實如此
Yes, yes indeed.
而洛基呢？And Loki?
他怎麼樣？What of him?
芬利爾甦醒了
Fenrir has awakened.
而洛基擁有兩半的護身符
And Loki has both halves of the amulet.
地震正在使這個星球的核心發生動搖
Earthquakes are-are shaking this planet to its core.
而洪水正在各地造成浩劫
And the flooding is wreaking havoc everywhere.
洛基靠近九界之樹了嗎？
Has Loki approached the tree of the Nine Realms?
我不確定 I'm not sure.
那麼時間就不在你這邊了，我的兒子
Then time is not on your side, my son.
你必須在野獸強大到足以直接吞噬
You must kill the beast before it gets strong enough
樹上的王國之前殺死它
to devour the realms straight from the tree.
我擔心這對他們來說要求太高了
I fear this is too much to ask of them.
他們? 對 凡人
Them? Yes. Mortals.
道德一直陪伴著我
Morals have been accompanying me in this,
而且他們一直在勇敢地幫助別人
and they've been valiant in their efforts to help.
幫助是好的
Help is good.
聽著，如果你不能收迴護身符
Listen, if you cannot reclaim the amulet,
那隻有一種其他的方法
there is only one other way
你可以摧毀芬利爾
you can destroy Fenrir.
那能創造的也可能毀滅
That which can create may also destroy.
父親...聯繫正在減弱
Father...the connection is weakening.
你知道，洛基在哪裡，他在哪裡？
Do you know, where is Loki, where is he?
北歐神符不夠牢固來保持聯絡
The Valknut is not strong enough to keep the connection.
在哪裡，父親？他們在哪裡？
Where, Father? Where are they?
洛基是...和芬利爾
Loki is...with Fenrir
在維格利德，戰場
in Vigrid, the fields of battle.
宇宙之間存在一座橋
There exists a bridge between worlds.
這是...It's...
這是一個山洞
it's a cave.
在那裡你會找到地獄的巨樹
There you will find Yggdrasil.
父親...Father...
父親! Father!
父親，請不要走！
Father, please don't go!
我們需要你 我需要你
We need you. I need you.
父親，求你了！
Father, please!
求你了，父親！
Please, Father!
我父親...他還活著
My father...he's alive.
我父親還活著！那很好，對嗎？
My father's alive! That's good, right?
是的，是的 是的 那還有希望
Yes, yes. Yes. There's still hope.
如果我們能找到洛基和芬利爾，並打敗他們
If we can find Loki and Fenrir, and defeat them.
所以他正在送援助？
So he's sending help?
不，他太虛弱了
No. He's far too weak for that.
他必須先恢復體力
He must regain his strength first.
我們不能等了
We can't wait.
我們有一個計畫
We have a plan.
我會找到洛基
I will find Loki.
他在哪裡？你父親告訴你了嗎？
Where is he? Did your father tell you?
是的 是的，他告訴我了
Yes. Yes, he did.
他接近芬利爾的墓 那有一個山洞
He's near Fenrir's tomb. There's a cave.
是的，我知道，我們在哪裡做了現場調查
Yes, I know, where we did our site survey.
它在挖掘和紅杉以東幾英哩處
It's a few miles east of the dig and the sequoias.
它在博伊登洞穴旁邊 它很深
It's by Boyden Cavern. It's very deep.
這座建築即將倒塌
This structure is going to collapse.
你會活下來的 我們不會
You'll survive. We won't.
我們必須離開屋頂
We have to get off the roof.
我理解這一點
I understand that.
但主要街道是
But Main Street is
現在在太平洋下面
under the Pacific Ocean right now.
這是我們最安全的地方，就在這裡
This is our safest place, right here.
我會去找洛基
I will go find Loki,
我會回來接你們兩個
and I will come back for you two.
也許我可以得到一架...
Maybe I can get one of the...
讚助人的直升機，但即使我能得到一架
benefactor's helicopters, but even if I can get one,
它必須離這水足夠遠
it'll have to be far enough away from this water.
等等 當然
Wait. Of course.
什麼? 你的主意
What? Your idea.
什麼主意？水
What idea? The water.
水 我不能用這條腿游泳
The water. I can't swim with this leg.
誰說過游泳的事？
Who said anything about swimming?
你有問題嗎？
Do you have a question?
數千 Thousands.
你為什麼離開地球？
Why did you leave Earth?
我從未離開過地球
I never left Earth.
我衹是不被需要
I just was not needed.
但現在你被需要了
But you're needed now.
來保護九界
To protect the Nine Realms.
是的 Yes.
為什麼拯救我們對你這麼重要？
Why does saving us mean so much to you?
你的世界是九界的一部分
Your world is a part of the Nine Realms.
而我是九界的保護者
And I am the protector of the Nine Realms.
我祖父...My grandfather...
他創造了這個世界
he created this world.
他為此付出了生命
He gave his life for it.
他的血肉
His flesh and blood.
造山以及造海
Made the mountains and the sea.
我父親奧丁...
My father Odin...
他是看守人
He was the caretaker.
這就是我遇見我心愛的希芙的地方
And this is where I met my beloved Sif.
啊，金髮女神
Ahh, the golden haired goddess.
她現在在哪裡？
Where is she now?
天堂...Asgard...
和我父親 with my father.
等等 你看到那了嗎？
Wait. You see that?
那裡，看到了嗎？
There, see?
烏鴉 The Ravens.
思想，記憶
Huginn, Muninn.
奧丁的信使
Odin's messengers.
它們只回答他
They only answer to him.
他說，如果可能的話，他會盡力提供幫助
He said he would try to send help if he could.
我們需要跟隨它們
We need to follow them.
你確定嗎？
Are you sure?
我肯定 他一定知道洛基在哪裡
I'm certain. He must know where Loki is.
他還會再送來更多幫助嗎？
Is he sending any more help?
我想我們需要所有能得到的幫助
I think we're going to need all the help we can get.
我不知道
I do not know.
送他的烏鴉可能花掉了
Sending his ravens may have spent
他僅剩的一點力量
what little power he has left,
但他知道這個世界有多寶貴
but he knows how valuable this world is.
它不能失落
It cannot fall.
我們需要把船靠岸並開始攀爬
We need to dock the ship and start climbing.
這次海嘯可能會帶來更多的海浪
We may get more waves with this tsunami.
我們有什麼選擇？
What choice do we have?
你還好嗎，尼克？
You okay, Nick?
我很好 讓我們繼續前進
I'm good. Let's keep going.
天堂像什麼?
What's Asgard like?
很像這個世界
Much like this world.
這是一件很棒的事情
It's a wonderful thing.
你的星球是美麗而且壯觀
Your planet is beautiful and spectacular.
然而洛基想摧毀它
Yet Loki wants to destroy it.
洛基不像我那樣看地球
Loki does not see Earth the way I see it.
他將地球視為力量和控制
He sees Earth as power and control.
有人告訴我洛基是個騙子
In the stories I was told Loki was a trickster,
一個煽動烏合之眾的人，而不是一個想摧毀王國的人
a rabble rouser, not someone who wanted to destroy the realm.
他試圖控制王國，但實際上
He seeks to control the realms, but in reality,
他衹是想為他的黑暗幻想找一個遊樂場
he just wants a playground for his dark fantasies.
洛基不開心，除非他欺騙了所有人
Loki's not happy unless he is tricking or deceiving everyone.
當他意識到自己衹是在愚弄自己時
He will not be happy when he realizes
他不會高興的
he's only fooling himself.
希望他永遠也到不了那裡
Let's hope he never gets there.
不幸的是，它是預先注定的
Unfortunately, it is pre-ordained.
芬利爾會長大，而它會吃掉這棵樹
Fenrir will grow, and he will devour the tree.
洛基會殺了我父親，奧丁
Loki will kill my father, Odin.
我以為你說過...
I thought you said that...
他注定要做這些事
He is destined for these things.
但你在這裡 你是來阻止它的，對嗎？
But you're here. You're here to stop it, right?
是的 Yes.
但你說這是命中注定的
But you said it was preordained.
洛基贏了 Loki wins.
每個故事都有個作者
Every story has a writer.
每個故事都有個再生戀
Every story has a predestiny.
但並非每個作家都是一樣的
But not every writer is the same.
不是每個故事都一樣
Not every story is the same.
所以有機會
So there's a chance
洛基的故事並沒有按他希望的方式結束
Loki's story doesn't end the way he wants it to.
現在你明白了
Now you are getting it.
好嗎，博士？很好
Okay, Doctor? Fine.
我們可以回來接你 不
We can come back for you. No.
我很好 I'm okay.
我可以背著你
You can get on my back.
呃，不，我沒事 謝謝
Uh, no, I'm okay. Thanks.
胡說，來吧!
Nonsense, come on.
好的 我們開始吧! 是的
Okay. Here we go. Yeah.
好的 索爾背著我
All right. Thor is carrying me.
這就是我們正在做的
That's what we're doing.
哦，是的 Oh, yep.
謝謝你 不客氣，朋友
Thank you. You're very welcome, friend.
烏鴉 The Ravens.
它們說洛基在這邊
They're saying Loki is this way.
我看不到另一個入口
I don't see another entrance.
還有別的路進去嗎？
Is there another way in?
讓我跟你談一下
Let me speak to you for a minute.
真的? 現在，在這裡？是的，是的 馬上
Really? Now, here? Yeah, yeah. Right now.
我們在這裡不屬於我們的聯盟
We're out of our league here.
我們將會幫忙
We're going to help.
我們在和眾神玩，以及他們的遊戲
We're playing with the gods, and their games.
我們衹是凡人
We're just mortals.
我理解 不，你不理解
I understand. No, you don't.
洛基一個人就夠危險的了
Loki's dangerous enough on his own.
但是芬利爾，這隻狼，完全是另一回事
But Fenrir, this wolf, it's a whole 'nother thing.
我們有索爾
We have Thor.
萬物滅絕 這是我們所知道的世界末日
Ragnarok. It's the end of the world as we know it.
這不是百分之百 足夠近
It's not 100%. Close enough.
這對我來說已經足夠了，嘿!
That's enough for me to try hey.
正如我的老導師曾經告訴我
As my old mentor used to tell me,
我們必須解決這個問題
we have to make this matter.
等等 Wait.
洛基在裡面 我能感覺到
Loki's in there. I can sense it.
走開 Move away.
跟我來，我能看到路
Stay with me. I can see the way.
沒有羞恥感
There's no shame.
你已經走了這麼遠
You've gotten this far.
不 No.
不，讓我們去踢一些北歐神的屁股，好嗎？
No, let's go kick some Norse god's ass, shall we?
來吧! Come on.
它是九界之樹
It's the Tree of Nine Realms.
九界之樹威力非常強大
The Tree of Nine Realms is very powerful.
洛基需要他所有的魔法和技巧來摧毀它
Loki will need all his magic and tricks to destroy it.
而一旦他摧毀了它呢？
And once he destroys it?
他會種一個新的
He will plant a new one.
一個他可以控制的
One that he can control.
然後他將控制宇宙中的所有領域
And then he will control all the realms in the universe.
我們如何阻止這一切？
How do we stop this?
你不能 You don't.
你太遲了 You're too late.
芬利爾，殺了他們！
Fenrir, kill them!
去，現在！Go, now!
來吧，索爾 Come on, Thor.
尼克? Nick?
來吧! Come on.
尼克! Nick!
回到這裡 Back here.
你沒事吧？Are you okay?
是的，是的，我想是的
Yeah, yeah, I think so.
你看到索爾了嗎？
Do you see Thor?
沒有 No.
格雷斯...Grace...
你知道他是個神，對吧？
You know he's a god, don't you?
誰會受傷
Who can get hurt.
我們必須找到他
We have to find him.
岩石是鬆散的 我想我們有一條出路
The rocks are loose. I think we have a way out.
我們得快點 好的，我們走吧!
We have to hurry. Okay, let's go.
哦，那傷口看起來很嚴重的，索爾
Oh, that wound looks nasty, Thor.
我希望它不會傷的太嚴重
I hope it doesn't hurt too much.
我不需要我的閃電
I do not need my lightning.
我可以用我的錘子打敗你
I can defeat you with my hammer.
芬利爾！Fenrir!
感受我的力量，索爾！
Feel my power, Thor!
適可而止 Enough is enough.
你在這 There you are.
索爾！Thor!
尼克，我們得做點什麼
Nick, we have to do something.
夠了這些愚蠢的舉動，凡人
Enough with this nonsense, mortals.
你贏不了！
You cannot win!
結束了 It's over.
我有完整的護身符
I have the complete amulet.
控制九界和大狼
Control of the Nine Realms and the Great Wolf
又是我的了
is mine once again.
如果你不介意的話，我有一棵樹要種
If you don't mind, I have a tree to plant.
索爾，我的兒子
Thor, my son.
醒來 Awake.
我在哪裡？Where am I?
這是什麼地方？
Where is this place?
你不認識你的家？
You don't recognize your home?
我的家？My home?
我的家 My home.
這是許多可能性之一
This is one of many possibilities.
但衹有一個是真實的
But only one can be real.
而那取決於你，以及你的決定
And that is up to you, and what you decide.
他們勢不可擋，父親
They are unstoppable, Father.
父親，我還能做什麼我還沒有做到的？
Father, what more can I do that I've not already done?
洪水 The floods.
洪水幾乎吞噬了地球
The floods have nearly consumed the earth.
而因為我的失敗，這棵樹幾乎死了
And the tree is almost dead because of my failure.
他們可能近了，但地球並沒有消失
They may be near, but the earth is not lost.
當地球人繼續戰鬥時，你為什麼認為失敗？
Why do you consider defeat when the Earthlings fight on?
他們可能有自己的問題
They may have their problems,
但當他們面對死亡時
but when they're faced with death,
他們迎頭衝了進來
they rush in head on.
他們會毫無顧慮地為正確的事業而死
They will die for the right cause without worry.
我們可以從他們身上學到很多
We could learn a lot from them.
你是天堂的索爾
You are Thor of Asgard.
奧丁的兒子
Son of Odin.
一個偉大，偉大的戰士
A great, great warrior.
雷和電在你的召喚下
Thunder and lightning beckon at your call.
我的力量不再回應我
My power no longer answers to me.
你的力量沒有離開你，我的兒子
Your power has not left you, my son,
它剛剛被芬利爾咬壞了
it has just been corrupted by Fenrir's bite.
沒有它我就不夠強壯
I am not strong enough without it.
你不需要打敗洛基
You don't need to defeat Loki.
萬物滅絕和野獸躺在一起
Ragnarok lies down with the Beast.
它總是這樣
It always has.
那野獸沒有弱點！
That beast has no weakness!
萬物都有弱點，我的兒子
Everything has a weakness, my son.
我不會把這項任務委託給你的
I would not have entrusted you with this task
如果我認為你做不到的話
if I did not think that you could do it.
記住你是誰
Remember who you are.
並記住你所擁有的
And remember what you have.
沒有你的力量我做不到，父親
I cannot do this without your strength, Father.
這是不可能的
It is impossible.
我的力量
My strength has
一直並將永遠與你同在
and always will be with you.
等等，爸爸，拜託 父親，請不要走
Wait, Father, please. Please don't go, Father.
請稍等，父親
Please wait, Father.
沒關係，我的兒子
It's all right, my son.
你衹有很短的路要走
You only have a short way to go.
地球需要你
The earth needs you.
你的朋友們，他們需要你
Your friends, they need you.
他們繼續戰鬥，但無法打敗洛基
They fight on, but they cannot defeat Loki.
他們需要雷神索爾
They need Thor, the God of Thunder.
索爾，住手！
Thor, stop this!
接受失敗 Accept defeat.
決不 Never.
那麼我會讓它成為一個快速而無痛地死去
Then I will make it a quick and painless death.
芬利爾，摧毀他！
Fenrir, destroy him!
索爾，毒牙！
Thor, the fang!
帕特裡克！Patrick!
你殺了芬利爾
You have killed Fenrir.
你殺了我的狼！
You have killed my wolf!
大地依然屹立，兄弟
The earth still stands, brother.
你沒有贏
You have not won.
你還在嘲笑我！
You still mock me!
我可能已經失去了王國，但我會復仇的
I may have lost the realms, but I will have vengeance.
我會永遠殺了你
I will kill you once and for all.
你殺不了奧丁
You couldn't kill Odin.
兄弟，你殺不了我的
Brother, you will not kill me.
奧丁走了 奧丁死了
Odin is gone. Odin is dead.
奧丁衹是一個幻覺！
Odin is but an illusion!
哦，愚蠢的兄弟
Oh, stupid brother.
你覺得我們是怎麼找到這個地方的？
How do you think we found this place?
即使被削弱了，奧丁還是設法打敗了你
Even weakened, Odin has managed to defeat you.
即使有你的計畫以及你的力量...
Even with your planning, and your power...
小心 而且你已失敗了
Careful. And you have failed.
因為那是你的命運，兄弟
Because that's your destiny, brother.
你總是會失敗！
You will always fail!
衹要有人反對你
As long as there is someone to oppose you.
不 No.
不，不！No, no!
地球永遠不會落到像你這樣的人手裡
Earth will never fall to the likes of you.
為何? How?
你衹是一個凡人！
You are but a mortal!
為何? How?
投降而我會饒了你的命，兄弟
Surrender and I will spare your life, brother.
饒了我？是的
Spare me? Yes.
饒了我，噢! 兄弟 別跟我胡說八道了
Spare me, oh brother. Spare me this nonsense.
請住手，兄弟，拜託
Please stop, brother, please.
那又怎麼樣？
So what?
我可以在監獄裡腐爛
I can rot in that prison
為了你無用的父親？
for your worthless father?
住手 住手Stop. Stop.
不，再也不會了 決不!
No, never again. Never!
不! 到此為止，兄弟！
No! This ends here, brother!
不! No!
洛基！Loki!
兄弟! Brother!
格雷斯 Grace.
格雷斯-格雷斯
Grace-Grace.
結束了嗎？Is it over?
洛基是...Is Loki...
洛基死了 Loki is dead.
結束了 It is over.
來，我們走
Come, let's go.
你的錘子，它很重
That hammer of yours, it's pretty heavy.
格雷斯，你是一個真正的戰士
You are a true warrior, Grace.
衹有有價值的人才可以揮舞雷神之錘
Only the worthy can wield Mjolnir.
尼克 Nick.
尼克! Nick!
結束了 It is over.
我們阻止了萬物滅絕
We stopped Ragnarok.
那現在怎麼辦？
So what now?
我以為你殺了芬利爾
I thought you killed Fenrir.
它應該死了！
He should be dead!
帕特裡克 Patrick.
格雷斯! Grace!
你沒事吧？Are you okay?
我們需要把他弄出去
We need to get him out of here.
他需要一個醫生
He needs a doctor.
哦，很高興見到你
Oh, good to see you.
地球還好嗎？
Is Earth okay?
它是 It is.
至少現在是這樣
At least for now.
這是個好兆頭
That's a good sign.
確實是個好兆頭
A good sign indeed.
他們叫我回到天堂的家
They call me home to Asgard.
我們還會再見到你嗎？
Will we see you again?
如果你需要我，我會回來的
If you need me, I will return.
你的世界是在我的保護之下
Your world is under my protection.
你說的是真的嗎？
Did you mean what you said?
關於華海拉殿的阿德裡安和葛列格？
About Adrian and Greg in Valhalla?
是的 你的朋友們將在眾神之中慶祝
Yes. Your friends will be celebrated amongst the gods.
我向你保證
You have my word.
仍然是一團糟
Still a mess.
今天這裡有很多人喪生
A lot of lives were lost here today.
是的，有
Yes, there were.
我為你的損失感到抱歉
I'm sorry for your losses.
謝謝你，我的朋友
Thank you, my friend.
謝謝大家
Thank you, all of you.
你真勇敢 You're so brave.
是時候了 It is time.
退後 Stand back.
好的 Okay.
所以我今天遇到了一個神
So I met a god today.
那比我的薪水等級高
That's above my pay grade.
老兄，那傢伙太棒了
Man, that guy's awesome.
是的，他是 Yeah, he is.
索爾! Thor!
父親 Father.
起來，我的兒子 起來
Rise, my son. Rise.
那你兄弟洛基呢？
And what of your brother, Loki?
父親，他是...
Father, he is...
他死了 he is dead.
他讓我別無選擇
He left me no choice.
他不願屈服
He would not yield.
如果我沒有阻止他
If I had not stopped him,
他會摧毀九界
he would have destroyed the Nine Realms.
我早該知道的
I should have known.
他是個傻瓜
He was a fool.
但他是我的兄弟，而我非常愛他
But he was my brother, and I loved him dearly.
然而...Still...
你做了件好事
you did something good.
地球人是一個有彈性的民族
The earthlings are a resilient people.
在危機時刻，他們走到一起
In times of crisis, they come together
來幫助他們的同伴
to help their fellow man.
多虧了你，他們纔有機會重建
Thanks to you, they have a chance to rebuild.
地球人和天堂
The earthlings and Asgard
將永遠欠你的債
will forever be in your debt.
哦，父親，我...
Oh, Father, I...
我不忍心告訴凡人
I did not have the heart to tell the mortals
芬利爾仍然活在這個護身符裡
that...Fenrir still lives in this amulet.
他的靈魂永遠
His soul forever.
所有這些都是預言
All of this was prophesized,
而結局是
and the end was
因為我們所有的決定
because of all of our decisions.
來 Come.
慶祝! Rejoice!
為九界歡樂吧...
Rejoice, for the Nine Realms...
再次處於和平狀態
are at peace once again.
索爾! Thor!
敬天堂! To Asgard!
敬天堂，我的兒子
To Asgard, my son.
是的，父親 Yes, Father.